# AMMAR ISRAR

## FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

### CONTACT

0331-5783334

ammarisrar28@gmail.com

ammarisrar.github.io

Street 105, Sector G-9/4, Islamabad

.....

## SKILLS

Angular ReactJS
ElectronJS Python
NextJS Django

RxJS Google Cloud Platform

Visual Studio Code MySQL DB Git & Atlassian Suite AWS

MongoDB NodeJS

\_\_\_\_\_

# TECHNOLOGY STACKS

MEAN (MongoDB, ExpressJS, Angular, NodeJS) MERN (MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS) MAD (MongoDB, Angular, Django)

\_\_\_\_\_

# EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering Iqra University, Islamabad Campus

2015-2019

- Awarded 5 academic scholarships for excellent academic performance
- Awarded gold medal for securing 3.78 CGPA

Higher Secondary School Certificate IMCB F-7/3, Islamabad

2012-2014

• Passed with Second Division

#### PROFILE

Motivated and passionate full-stack developer with proven industry experience developing multiple products in the Robotic Process Automation (RPA) domain. Experience in multiple tech stacks like MAD, MEAN and MERN stack. Responsible for overall code structure, UI implementation, responsiveness, code optimizations, and API integrations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

# Full-stack Developer | Sales Engineer

#### **UpStart Commerce**

FEB 2024 - MAY 2024

- Responsible for bringing new ideas for the sales teams to add to the client demo site, to attract more potential customers.
- Responsible for updating the client demo website to showcase our composable ecommerce platform.
  - Written using TypeScript React.
  - o Framework was NextJS, powered by Contentful and Alokai Storefront UI.
- Responsible for cleaning, adjusting and adding new data to the platform for a more personalized demo.

### **Full-stack Developer**

#### MM / Autosphere

JAN 2020 - JAN 2024

- Responsible for developing multiple enterprise MEAN stack applications (focused on system automation), from designing the architecture to complete development.
- Responsible for creating and updating ReactJS components for JupyterLab extensions.
- Created a complete dashboard from scratch using Angular.
- Created a companion tray using Angular and ElectronJS.
- Added different types of Highcharts.
- Used Angular Material and Google Fonts for typography.
- Implemented communication with Jenkins by consuming its APIs.
- Implemented efficient stream management using RxJS.
- Collaborated with multiple teams to help refine their business requirements.
- Delivered multiple knowledge sharing sessions regarding different technologies and design patterns.
- · Optimize application performance through code refactoring.
  - ---- Offshore employment at Qvantel ----
- Added features and fixed bugs in CSR application for Jazz Pakistan.
  - These features include components from the SIM card issuance and update flows.
  - This module was written in Python (django).
  - Responsible for writing REST APIs in django REST Framework (DRF).
  - Written unit tests using PyTest
  - ---- Offshore employment at Ai-XPRT ----
- Used ABBYY FineReader OCR to extract the data from customer invoices, and to parse it for auditing purposes.
- Responsible for working on the parser logic, to clean the data to present to the frontend.
- Responsible for writing and updating the logic for auditing.
  - o This logic was written in native Python language.

## LANGUAGES

English	
Hrdu	

## **PROJECTS**

## Sentiment Analysis on Google Cloud Platform

- Responsible for creating the architecture to use multiple cloud services for sentiment analysis.
- The system would take an image, perform sentiment analysis on it, create a JSON, store it in the database and Tableau would pick this information to populate graphs.
  - Used Compute Engine for compute, Cloud Storage for database, and Vision API for sentiment analysis.

# Sales data forecasting using Time-series Analysis in Electron Framework Final Year Project

- Responsible for creating an Electron JS application which takes in a CSV file, and creates a trend for future values.
  - o Uses Facebook Prophet as the backend.
  - o Graphs are shown on the frontend powered by Highcharts.